Guys,
last week was awesome with Schnitzel making that announcement, and now we gotta do it the next week, this week, today with Ryan Yep. Leading Mujina Femi.
This is gonna be so freaking cool. Yep. Ryan, welcome to the show.
Thanks, guys.
Glad to be here.
Yeah, man.
Sorry for the technical difficulties.
Yesterday Rod.
We could just
Oh, sorry. No. Everything's Ryan, it's a huge pleasure to have you here.
Thank you, Rob.
You want me to do a little intro? You wanna you need to go TT? What do you need to do?
By the way, Dan top last week's lot lizard
intro.
Oh god. That was Take it away. Take it away, Rod. Like,
I'm on the deep end. The lot lizards and then they, I'll give Rob a lot of credit on this one, which was
his little riff on the f one fifty Tundra in
comparing
what the Bitcoin veterans were doing compared to, like, all the
interpretive dance people. Yeah. They mess around. That was So we're hosting grassroots Bitcoin week here at the park, and,
we had bit another amazing bit devs led by, Steve Myers with, Rob Hamilton came on as a cohost from Anchor Watch. It was awesome.
And then we had Grassroots Bitcoin
yesterday
where it's a meet up meet up organizers. We had meet up organizers from all over The US, predominantly
here hanging out. And then last night, we had Evan Mawari,
who wrote this awesome book called Crazy Epic Courage. Unbelievable.
He's a, human rights activist, but predominantly
known for helping overthrow,
Robert McCarthy.
Oh, wow. Dictator in Zimbabwe. I mean, his story is unbelievable. Crazy.
That's the dude that was just in here? Yeah. Just like a brother just in here.
It's my claim to fame now. I shook that man's hand. Yeah. Heck yeah. He's pastor Evan
live on Twitter. Okay. Awesome.
And,
he
yeah. He's just he's an awesome human being. And then now we're doing today, me premiere Bitcoin
Bitcoin educators on conference. So, anyways, that's a long winded way of saying sorry, Ryan, for
not launching yesterday and Scott.
I blame Rob, but,
for not keeping me on schedule. I'll take the heat.
But, no, this is gonna be
epic,
and I'm really excited to share what
you're going to be or what you're started working on and what you're planning to work on.
And I'm gonna have Eco kind of, take the lead here.
Sure. Yeah.
You know, this is the the second project that we're
discussing on the podcast.
I mean, I guess third if you count ember one because we're Yeah. Yeah. For sure. We've talked about ember one a lot, Scott. But like you mentioned, by the way, tangent, can we just go how's Amber one coming along, Scott?
It's going great. Everything's fine. Don't worry.
Love it.
I'm imagining,
you know, the background of, like, the house being burned down. He's like, everything's
fine. Scott's, like, you know, skateboarding
and just, like, having his latte.
No. We're gonna it's gonna be it'll knock your socks off.
Got twenty days. Right, guys? That's right. Twenty days. That's right.
Yeah. No. I'm I'm not worried.
Yeah. No. We're good. This is this is totally the problem in the course of developing new hardware. It is. It is, actually. If this doesn't happen, you're just not pushing it enough.
Exactly.
That is one thing where, you know, in hardware, especially is, like,
I'm cursory following along with you guys.
When things break
or blow up, like, software is like, oh, that's a bug. I gotta fix it and so on. Where in your guys' hardware world, you're like,
bang, pop.
What was that noise?
Oh, shit.
Something's on fire.
I gotta go fix that, like, right now. Not I'll get back to that in a minute.
And,
so I've I've a new appreciation for you guys, and I appreciate you keeping your,
timelines and deadlines. Yep. That's for sure. We got this dialed in. Good. Don't you worry. Any more updates you guys wanna share or you guys, just say? About Amber one? Yeah.
I mean,
Scott can speak to it better than I can, but, you know, from
from what I'm seeing, we're, you know, we're right on track. Perfect.
There's been a couple bumps in the road, but, I mean, Scott is negotiating those obstacles like a champ.
And he knows exactly what to do. And we'll touch base and bounce ideas off each other, and then he'll check this, he'll check that, he'll have this breakthrough, and then, you know, we're up and on our way again
off to the races and hitting the next obstacle and then eating it for breakfast.
Oh. That's good. Not his first rodeo. That was a that was a good way to put it.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, we're we're
we're
we're in uncharted territory. We're we're moving fast, breaking things,
but that's that's what keeps it interesting.
Yeah. You know, if dismantling the proprietary mining empire were easy, someone would have done it by now. That's right. That's fair. Okay. Alright. That was fair. Okay.
Well Speaking of dismantling the proprietary,
mining empire That's right. This is like a core piece to it. Yes. So let's talk about the Mujina firmware project. Yeah. So when we were trying to figure out, like,
what
we're going to do to dismantle the proprietary mining empire, firmware was,
firmware for the hash that's it's really like the heart of the project. Like, it connects all the pieces together.
So,
we
wrote our basic ideas out. Ryan was one of several developers that applied,
and he stood out among the rest to us.
And we interviewed him, got some good vibes on him,
and started negotiating, like, what the terms would look like. And we came to
to an agreement and
got your stamp of approval,
and now we're here, and we're in our first week of the of the grant cycle.
Is this where the lot lizards show up?
That's for post post shipping.
I see. Okay. All the lot lizards.
You want them we'll go get them. You you never wanna let your guard down. They could come out at any time.
I've got the sticker
on my,
truck door. This is No lizards.
I wanna get one now. If you could find a source, that would be fun to stick them on random people's
vehicles at gas stations. You just have, like, a few homes with, like, lot of the fruit.
All of a sudden, you got random girls just knocking on windows.
Ryan's like, who am I writing for more for? That you don't wanna deal with.
But,
this house in Texas is gonna be
lit.
Yeah.
We haven't even gotten to the cuddle puddle.
Oh, I heard that. Yeah. I heard that one too.
Why it's like all that? I just wanna I just wanna ship stuff, man. I wanna do I'm gonna be staying in the other apartment, the non cuddle puddle apartment.
You know, there's gonna be, like, how they put, like, a tie on the doorknob or, like, a a pineapple that's upside down. Oh, god. That'll be, like, cuddle puddle approved rooms.
If the bid access hanging upside down, that means
Rob's Rob's bringing this Hugh Hefner robe over. He's like, hey, guys.
Are we here to dismantle the proprietary mining empire or what? It's like, no, Rob.
That's the wrong empire you're trying to dismantle.
Maybe in my next life.
You have one of those robes, though. Right?
I have a robe. It's not silk or anything. Don't get me wrong. But a robe is not a robe is not great because you get out of the shower, you get dry,
and then I don't wanna just
stay mostly naked
in my house. And the robe goes on after the shower. Like, I wanna get dressed. I have stuff to do.
So I have a robe, not not in rotation. Not in rotation.
No time.
That's what I'm saying. No time for robes.
So to bring us back to firmware. Right? So we got this initial. We did the proposal.
And then what was it about you mentioned vibes. What about Ryan's vibes are so
so immaculate?
What what sets you off? What did he say? Well, the the dead give the dead giveaway was that he wasn't sure he was the best candidate.
And that that's usually the guy that's gonna do the best job is the guy that doesn't really wanna do it.
So I definitely picked him. Not saying that you didn't wanna do it. I mean, he was super stoked, super grateful, but, you know, he was just like he was like, man, you know, I haven't I haven't really built anything Bitcoin specific
yet, but, you know, I've got, like, twenty years of embedded Linux design experience. Twenty
honestly and and and then I'm gonna pass it to Ryan to kind of explain why,
you wanna do this and and then get
dive deep into your experience. But that night or the next day after we solo mine that block, we got a ton of applications. Obviously, they're like, wait. There's Bitcoin over here. We can go, Ryan,
I mean and our type form kinda sucks too. It's like, you know, one link.
I don't know if you did this out on a Google Doc or something, and then you pasted it in. But it was, like, one of the most long detailed applications
submissions that we we got, and it was awesome. So,
Ryan, why why are you doing this, man?
Yeah.
Well, I was I was in the audience that night when we mined that block,
and that was just so exciting.
But, yeah, as as you know, like, so I've been,
I'm in Chicago. I'm an out of town Bitcoin Park member.
So I'll come down for
I think that was my third mining summit,
Nashville Energy Mining Summit.
So and I so I've been lurking,
let's say, for many for
up up to three years, I guess, around the park just waiting for,
you know, the right
opportunity to come along. Like, what what can I contribute to? And I've been looking for looking for a long time. In fact, I guess, I remember
what year was it going to the the big Bitcoin conference
be before
I really knew who all the right people to talk to in the space were? I remember walking out on the trade show floor
and heading for the mining equipment because, you know, I'm a
an embedded Linux guy. I'm a a hardware guy. So so I'm I'm like, the mining part of Bitcoin is interesting to me. Maybe that's somewhere I could find something to work on.
And so I remember hitting up what must have been, like, a bit main rep on the trade show floor
and just I just assumed
that this stuff was somewhat open,
that you could, you know, download the software and that you could tweak things or there were
you know, I don't know if I believed schematics were available, but I had no idea how closed this whole ecosystem was. And so I completely innocently just was talking to a a Bitmain rep.
He's like, no. We don't really advise people tinker with the firmware. Like, no. You don't. It just doesn't it doesn't happen. And I
so I was a little discouraged by that. I think later on in that same conference, I
I attended a,
a panel talk with Marshall Long. I don't know if he remembers me. I have to see if he does.
And I'm like
afterwards, I talked to him. I kinda tell him, like, hey. I work on this stuff for a living, like, non Bitcoin stuff, but similar hardware. Like,
I would love to get involved. And he's like, Oh yeah, man, you should. It's a total shit show.
Accurate.
Yeah. Anyway, so fast forward two years, you know, I've known you, Rod, for for a while around the park, most of you guys.
I can't believe that this $2.56 foundation thing was just kind of growing right under my nose because
when I heard
so that night, you the you know, at the telehash,
we introduced
all the projects and talked about them and what the what kind of the vision and the mission of the foundation was.
And, you know, for me, it really had nothing to do with hitting that block, although that was exciting. I was just like, oh my gosh, this project they're describing, that is an exact fit for my skill set
and an exact like, I have a real passion to see this stuff opened up and usable and open source.
So it it was the perfect fit. I after that after that, I think I banged out that whole application
from
the room above the event space and be going I like, before I even left the park, I had sent that to you guys because I'm just like,
I'll talk to you in person, but I just wanted to get get my foot in that door just so you knew, like, how excited I was. So I'm really
You you came up and introduced yourself to me, and I if I recall correctly, it was prior to us hitting the block.
Yeah. I think so.
And you mentioned you know, you
you let me know that you were interested in working on the firmware or just, like, trying to contribute in any way possible if there is any way we could do something and,
yeah, and here we are. Yeah. I just wanted to work on this. I mean, not I guess now that you're committed to the grant, I can say, like, I would have worked on this no matter what. I think
We all got paid?
Wow.
I wouldn't have had as much time as I will have now to work. But There you go. Yeah. I think I told you in the application, like, hey. I'll be the lead developer if you want me to be, but
otherwise, I'm just here to contribute.
Yeah.
I'll be a contributor if I have to be because this is this is this lines up with what I wanna do.
And, Scott, like, how does this, like, impact the work? And, like, and what do you think about, like, a guy like Ryan kinda working
on this project?
That story that you told about Bitmain, I I hadn't heard that from you before, Ryan. That that's just fantastic. Like,
to think that
you know, there's people out here such as yourself with so much experience and desire
to do this and to be working on this stuff and to just kinda, like, get shut down by the incumbents that control, like, 80%
or more of the market
is insane. And I'm really glad that, like, all these,
you know, various things have come together to get us to this point such that
you are working on this now.
I mean, I I really, really think
that the entire mining industry is hampered by the closed source nature of the firmware.
Hardware too, but firmware
especially. Like
nobody likes this,
except for maybe Bitmain. But, like,
I I swear, like, big, large, extreme, all the way down to the smallest miners, no one is benefiting
from
this closed source, like, adversarial relationship between the manufacturers
and the the customers.
Mhmm.
So, yeah, to get to get mining where it needs to be in the future, we've got to have open source firmware, and
we just gotta do it. We gotta do it. I think we're in really good hands with you and your your previous experience,
lots of previous experience doing this kind of thing.
I've I've told you all this before, but, I mean, this of all the two fifty six foundation projects, this is the biggest one for sure. It's a really big project. There's a lot of different hardware
that,
can that this framework can come across, and there's a lot of a lot of people
who have a lot of different ideas about what they wanna do
with this firmware and mining.
And
that's great. That's what we need in Bitcoin mining is a lot of different people with a lot of different ideas.
But,
I think to have the firmware
benefit the the largest number of people is
a big job. So not to, like, freak you out about it. Could you guys go deeper on that, though?
Could could you take a little bit deeper and, like, detail some of those issues? Because, like, Ryan's sitting here, like,
very humble. I don't wanna
oversell this because he understands the scope of the problem. Now Scott's here, like,
this is an insanely big, task to undertake.
Can you help can you help the smooth brains like Rod and myself like unpack that a little bit? What the fuck?
It's so Busted.
We're in good company. Absolutely everything about the future of humanity rides on you, Ryan. So
With great power comes great responsibility. Okay. There we go.
Yeah. We're just we're just getting credit here.
Go ahead. Well, I I'll tell the story like this.
So I went to school to be a double e.
In fact, that's what I, you know, I did graduate with an electrical engineering degree. Right on.
Sorry. Clarify.
That's just shorthand
for saying that you're like the
the theoretical physicist of the engineering world. You're the most cracked of all engineers.
Well, I did spend
a lot of time in the library at school. But,
no. So,
thought I was gonna be a double e,
and then at some point, I got introduced to the world of software, and then I'm like,
oh, this is really cool. Like,
it's the software that makes all the hardware work.
So that's where I wanna be.
And so I say that to say that, like,
at least these days, you know, no piece of hardware
works without a ton of software on top of it.
So I guess that's where the
the central
importance
of the firmware
emerges. Right? Like, you can't do anything with any of this hardware without software to run it.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
It enables so much. You know, for those who don't know, the the sort of software of hardware is embedded systems. And,
you know, these
electronics,
the hardware,
just doesn't really do much until the firmware comes along,
and and
interfaces it with the the rest of the world, the network.
It's it's it's where the magic happens. It gets pretty crazy, complicated.
What are some crazy applications? Let's let's fast forward six months, you know, nine months. We got this out there.
What are some of the, you know, Puck like, CleanSparks coming, giving us, like, you know, tens of millions of dollars of money, Core Scientific, Riot. They're they're kissing us, you know, hugging us, whatever we want, you know, blah blah blah. Why are they so supportive of us from the Pubcos to also even the the the smaller miners?
The why are the heat punks excited? Why why is everyone excited? Maybe accept Bitmain.
Because they they've all got great ideas. We we've heard from lots of different people.
Troy Cross had an article in the last issue of,
Bitcoin Magazine.
It talks about
all these issue all these different ways
that Bitcoin miners can be used.
This is the stranded energy. This is the
monetizing
different generation,
strategies. This is,
heat reuse.
These are massive,
massive things. Right? Like, getting,
you know, heat reuse means you're basically generating Bitcoin by mining and you're reusing the heat. So that cost of the the heat
comes down. And it it can enable all kinds of
different applications. I'll, you know, leave that to exercise for the listener. But if you go out there, Troy Cross,
has talked about all sorts of them, but the heat punks, Tyler Stevens has just put out a book talking about some of them.
Rob Warren, author of the, the fantastic Bitcoin Miners' Almanac,
touches on this kind of stuff.
Tons of applications. Right? But I think we are
at kind of a standstill in actually making them happen
because it's so the the machines that are out there, the equipment that's out there, the firmware that's out there for Bitcoin mining
does not support any of these things. It doesn't enable them. It doesn't make them any easier.
And there's this adversarial relationship, meaning you have to actually, like, reverse engineer and hack these machines to get them to become
a space heater,
and there's no other options. So So just think about the simple thing about a space heater, you know, you just plug it in your bathroom,
you know, so that when you have that that time between when you get out of the shower and when you put your robe on, so it's very pleasant for you in the bathroom,
you have a space heater in there. That could be a Bitcoin miner. In fact, that's an
an epic
example of what a Bitcoin miner can be doing. So you're not just paying for that heat,
directly with a resistive heater. You're also mining Bitcoin in your in the spare time. And there's a lot of,
there's a lot of space heaters out there. Like, we we have to just capture a tiny little fraction of the space heater market to have an absolutely
insanely large bitcoin mining decentralized
bitcoin mining force out there. So
okay. Space heater.
Right now, you can take an s nine and you can put it in there, but an s nine is an industrial Bitcoin miner. It has things like ethernet.
It has
firmware that optimizes for the highest hash rate. Those that's not what you want in a space heater. You don't wanna have to plug ethernet into your space heater. You wanna have your space heater controlled by a thermostat, not just the highest hash rate ever. Is it just these simple little things that is an absolute battle right now with the current closed source hardware and firmware ecosystem.
Yeah.
I'll
one example.
So I was out at the Heat Punk Summit in Denver, shout out to the space
and Tyler,
about a month ago,
and they had in their kitchen area, they had all sorts of different projects. I've never seen so many Bitcoin heating projects in one place. It was very cool.
But I was talking to this one guy who had embedded,
I don't know, two or four
s 19
in in what looked like a heater,
like the kind of HVAC system you'd put in your four of them. Yeah. Yeah. It's like m 30 or something.
Checking out how he built it or whatever.
He literally had a thermostat
drop you know, connected to a a relay
turning 240
volt power on and off to just the whole system.
That was the level of control.
I mean, I
it's so you're literally turn you know, you're literally pulling the plug on a Linux computer
every time you wanna turn the thing off. Like, I mean, everyone should be able to understand that's just not the way you build
a system, but they really don't have much choice with the hardware they're given and the software they're given today. So
I'm amazed of the things that people have built despite
not having parts to work with.
It is really cool. It is really cool what people have built. Yeah. I'm glad you got it. When we're in Africa and the gridless guys, we're talking about how they're helping, like, regulate the power on the grids. They're just flipping their miners on and off, like,
to account for
the demand and and
the lack of demand on the grid at any given time. Yeah. And Crazy.
And it's because, you know, everybody's
been everyone is
I shouldn't generalize that much. A lot of people have recognized that Bitcoin miners can can be useful in other ways than just sitting on a rack in a warehouse.
But that's what
99%
of the market has been designed to do, is just live on a rack in a warehouse. Mhmm. And until there's an open source firmware,
there's not gonna really be a a good way
short of, like like, Frankenstein in some relays and a and a thermostat in the box with the miners to control them. Like,
you
having the firmware unlocked gives you so many more options and, like, elegant solutions,
and you can actually start
setting up operations
that are efficient for
your specific task
that is something different than just running a warehouse full of miners.
And that starts with the firmware. And, like, you know, here we are. There there's a lot of aftermarket firmware solutions,
so you can flash
something other than Bitmain's firmware on your Antminer.
Like,
What's the one of the, Well, there's brains OS. There's vNISH. VNISH. Yeah. I think KaboomRacks
had their own Yep. Flavor of v niche.
But none of those aftermarket
firmwares are open source. So users are still limited
by,
what those particular developers decided to make accessible to them. The number of applications and people that could be building on all of
Mougina firmware project,
is, like, mind boggling to me. And it's like, once this goes out there, like, to your point, Ryan, when you're, like, like, at the heat pump summit and to you guys just, like, use these applications,
that's gonna just compound and get the next wave of people just coming in and working on this stuff. And they may not even know that it's just, like, Bitcoin. It's like, no. This is just the best use. And by the way, there's, like, some, like, magic Internet money that works here that we're able to actually
for some reason, they gave me this deal on my,
you know,
shower heater. By the way, I would upsell a nice, like, branded robe for them that go ties it all together. Yeah.
Brains has robes.
Exactly. See, Brains made some for the heat pump. Ahead of the game right there. Yeah. Ryan, I wanted to I wanted to ask you on the front of
building this this because you have to build the the software with a lot of the physical
machine in mind, which is this weird, like
I'm imagining you're kinda doing this dance between
programming.
In programming, you're not necessarily thinking about
the discrete
architecture of the thing that runs your your, your code because it tends to be pretty,
pretty general or you can just kind of disaggregate it into the cloud.
How how much does having an open source control board
impact what you're going to be doing with the Magina firmware?
Well, that that's,
that opens the door for us to do everything,
anything and everything we want,
especially
as we move toward putting
other chips on other Ember
boards in the future
that have open specifications.
And I listened to
you guys talk last week with Schnitzel about all the things he wants to put on the control board.
How when he builds something today, he normally has to have
you know, in addition to
the control board that's controlling his
hash boards, he has additional boards on the side
to
connect to his sensors and his you know, all the controls he does for the system he's building.
Well, because we're building an open because we're building a control board of our own,
we
can do all of that in one place now, and I think he's really excited about that. So that's one of the jobs of our firmware is to enable
all of the
the stuff he's doing in hardware
Mhmm. To bring additional sensors and controls
to the table.
The Magina firmware will support all of those things
and make it easy for people to write their own programs that run on the control board
that
do application specific things with all of those inputs and outputs.
And,
another benefit of it being open source is that
if this
board doesn't exactly suit the thing you want to build,
then this is a reference design for you to Yep. Start with Mhmm. And augment to add you know, maybe there's some
set of high power
relays you need in your system, and so you kinda take an ember one,
or sorry, the you take a Libre open
hardware design, and you add your your own high powered relays to it.
And,
yeah, openness is everything. I, you know, I come from a world in embedded Linux where
almost everything we do except the very application specific part of it, you know, for all sorts of products. It's it's all the amount of open software
and open ecosystem
where
where people you would you would think on the outside are competitors,
competitor companies, you know,
the are actually collaborators
on the majority, you know, behind the scenes on all the software. You know, the Linux kernel is
everybody everybody works and contributes on that, even people who are fierce competitors in the marketplace,
because that's not
where they differentiate
their products. You know? So
us kind of seeding
this ecosystem with open hardware and open software
kicks off,
I think, a new era where
people can build
and share
and,
you know, I I mean, our vision is that this turns into the the Linux of mining. Right? You know, that's why we're making this open from the beginning. That's why even though
things like brains OS exists,
the third party frameworks exist.
Yeah. Our biggest feature is ours is going to be open. Ours is something that everyone is going to contribute to. So this is going to be the shared hub
where everybody working on mining equipment like this.
And, you know,
maybe part of dismantling
the proprietary,
mining
empire is that eventually they just give up and become contributors.
You know? They're welcome to build industrial miners out of this stuff same stuff too. Right?
Exactly. So that's You got that would be sad. It's past
past time that open source
came to this part of Bitcoin.
That's right.
Amen, bro. And
and it'll be so cool the day when that happens,
because now is a nonzero chance, especially with you on on on the team.
That's for sure.
Real quick,
do you wanna get the do we have the the the Hashers? I wanna give a shout out to those Hashers
before
we we get near our end of time. Come on, Rob.
I'm ready. Don't think I'm not ready. Don't think I have a
a collection of tabs
that would Yeah. Like you're not impressed.
Blow your mind. He's got it up because
Starting with Lin coin, we have LeZabler.
Let's go. Followed by Schnitzel Axe.
Thank you, Schnitzel, for continuing to
rip that hash out from the shop and for showing us your fish tank. It was beautiful. That was cool. Oh, yeah. Another shout out to Kuma, the best doggy ever. Brain cancer, you suck. Hoping that the brain cancer treatments continue to go well for doggy, Kuma. Moving over to public pool,
we have hacked the planet. Hacked the planet. Fantastic.
We also
well, no. That's enough. That's enough, public pool. We had a good time. But we're moving now to Ocean Pool. Rod's office get box. Is it on there?
On public pool? Yeah.
Turn around. Is it not working?
It's overheated, Rod.
Oh.
Oh. Did you unplug the fan?
We turned it down a little bit. Yeah. Sometimes if you, like, turn the hot spot fan control off Yeah. Move it to 20%, I think. You put on 20%.
Too low. Man. Yeah. It'll No overclocking in this office.
Well, no hashing in this office either.
Sorry to hear that public pool and get your contributions up. Yeah. Those are really quiet. Okay. And it can just run at full speed, and it won't interfere with all your meetings.
My deals. Yeah. Your deals. We don't have a deal with Noctua yet, though, so we have to refrain from shouting them out too hard. You got an LPS part that's great. With,
much more advanced fan control algorithm. There you go. So Oh, for the Bendix? Yeah. Hell, yes.
Moving on to ocean.xyz.
Everybody loves ocean, the data datum protocol.
We have bible huddle. Great job. Thank you, bible huddle, for continuing to bless us with your your terra hash.
We have trump's america
dot expose.
Looks like we have some political
advertising happening.
I'm now going to be going to Trump's America dot exposed probably on
a library computer.
We then have dotexplorers? Is that a real domain name? That's what it says. I'm not going to type it into my computer, but I would like type yeah. Maybe
if I open an anonymous shit. What if I do it on my phone? I'll figure it out later. We then have Borst,
the
one, the only,
one of our favorites who we love, mister Borst himself,
running straddle.work.tangent.
This is this is one of the many reasons why I love doing project like the two z six foundations.
Guys like Ryan, Schnitzel,
Forest,
all of a sudden that they're just, like, such hardcore builders in their own right. Like,
this becomes a a kind of a community platform for them to engage and show their proof of work because they're finally, like, okay. This is where I can contribute.
I I I think there's, like, hundreds of these guys out there. Yeah. And, hopefully,
the two fifty six Foundation could continue to pull them Yeah. Pull them in. Yeah. It's our long it's our goal that each of these projects become long term supported
initiatives. Yeah. Like, literally on their own. Like Yeah. Holy cow.
Like, once you get the best people, you don't let them go. Like, the fact that we have folks like this. The fact that we have Ryan in our community who's like, oh, yeah. I've been doing this thing for twenty years. Yeah.
Don't mind me while I just help you figure out the core problem of Bitcoin mining firmware.
I've been just sharpening my blade. Unbelievable.
Let me get the last shout out out to bit ax wannabe Justin s seventeen crow. Legend. Thank you for your ongoing contributions. You know who's not there?
Bikes and Bitcoin. Bikes and Bitcoin is not
there. My
s nine my base in S 9 is apparently
very dead.
Yes. And that's all. Those are our hash How cool is it gonna be
Go ahead, Harv. How cool is it gonna be when we have Amber one board showing up in that list?
Yeah. That's
gonna be cool. Yeah.
Yep. I'd left it on 15 volts. It would be.
What'd you get it up to, though?
24.
Hey, buddy. What does it look like now?
What does it look like? Actually, what does it smell like?
It it has a hole in it. I I I have since replaced all the,
charred
components.
Nice.
Oh, nice.
Yeah.
No. We're not we're not stopping there. We'll set that. Testing data for Ryan in the future. Yeah. That's all we're doing. We're just getting some testing data for Ryan. We have kind of this little like snow drift of like parts that are like in the corner. I've just taken them off and they're like over there.
Souvenirs.
I'll note that it was not the software's fault.
This
time. How could it be? Never is. Software is always perfect.
It was a solder. Must have been a bad solder.
So with the last five minutes, I also wanna give a shout out to Foundry initial support,
Heatbit with a massive initial support to kinda kick start the two fifty six Foundation Mhmm. And HRF.
Like Amazing.
I'm kind
of thinking about these in tranches, and I'm, like, a little nervous about the telehatch. The telehatch is gonna be great. It's gonna be beautiful. It's gonna have so much hash rate. It's gonna be amazing. We're gonna say stop. We're gonna have so much hash rates. Stop sending you hash rates. It's too much. Hash rate. It's too much. We have too much.
But no. Seriously, we need more.
We need to have a lot.
We need all that. We need all of it. Like, please be familiar.
Telash on Monday, May 5, and then the the Texas Energy Mining Summit. All of the,
guys from the two fifty six foundation project leads are gonna be there. Yep. Ryan, Scott,
Domenico,
and then another person Yeah. Schnitzel.
That other person's gonna come on next week. Right? Well, no. We we announced it on Twitter, Colpreet. Colpreet. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Good. Yeah. What were you didn't want me to say? Well, I I forgot that I had announced it on Twitter. Cool. So Kulprit's gonna come on next week. I didn't wanna let the cat out of the bag.
No worries.
So it'd be cool to have all of them together. And I think at ease each of these energy mining summits always tying a telehash,
even though I'm gonna have probably so much egg on my face when we have, like, 10 terra hash pointed to us during the telehash number two. But, Hey. It's not zero.
Let's go. Boom.
But that'll be dope.
One one thing with the last five minutes, like, Ryan,
you know, in this next kind of six months,
what's
like, when you're done with this project and you're like, alright. I fulfilled my kind of grant.
What what are you gonna be feeling, and what does, like, success look like to you?
What does success look like?
Well, obviously, this
works, and
we have
our system showing up in that hash list Rob just read.
Okay. That's what I wanna yeah. Exactly.
Yep. But,
yeah, I also wanna say, like,
you know, my role
is to get the this ball rolling.
Right?
To to lay some rails
and to,
you know, be a guaranteed driving force to get this initial system working. But success,
you know, toward the end of the project looks like we kind of successfully launched this as a community thing.
You know? Eventually,
this isn't just this whole thing this isn't just Ryan writing firmware to save the world. Right? Like, I'm just here to help get it started.
But we wanna turn this into a true
community
project,
you know, where
for a while, I'm I'm just the shepherd shepherd for a while. So
that's that's part of success in my mind too is is,
gradually
getting people contributing,
besides me
and, you know, kind of selling that
selling people on this vision, getting getting people
to contribute back to the project.
See, that's the thing. Like and I gotta it reminded me. I gotta dust off this book. I don't think I ever finished it. It was like the history of open source
software, and it kinda,
explained what were the common denominators
on the successful open source projects. And it always really you could go back to one person, like Linux, Linus. Right?
Torvald. You know, like, you can go back to Scott, Bitax. I know you don't wanna take a lot. Like, there's that one person that was, like, fed up or just wanted to do it and then was the driving force
and really got this thing going and was pushing it, not only from a development side, but from
a communication side, like explaining
what this is and showing the proof of work on why this is impactful. So, like, that's what I mean, that's why I'm so bullish on you leading this. It's like you setting up these rails,
leveraging the two fifty six foundation. Hopefully, Iko and Scott and maybe Rob as good shepherds of communication of, like, what this is all about such that we can bring in even more people
to start contributing and tinkering on this project. Because in a dream scenario from there,
we have, like, five of these foundations on their own. And then all of a sudden, I could see a world where the two fifty six foundation kinda slowly
fades into the background, and it's just like these projects are the projects in the space. Yeah. And they can stand on their own two legs. Totally. Yep.
But Open source is that decentralized development that we need. So, you know, the getting more people involved, more different groups involved is what secures this,
in the future. Right? There's no single
group or party to go after to shut it down or co opt it.
And I know I'm the one that's kinda I need to end this, but I I
what about
you know, these hackathons are really interesting to me. They're working in San Francisco. They're working in these other areas. You know, with the telehash,
combining
because the university side, Ryan, you know, maybe there's, like, young,
engineers that want may wanna tinker with what we're working on.
You know, there's something that could be there, and there could be grant money that we could go and tap into for prizes
to really help pour a little gasoline on this fire. So that may be something, you know, we should we should consider and look into as well. Interesting to incorporate, like, a hackathon component with the telehashes.
Totally. Actually, that's actually not a bad idea. Yeah. So, like, around the telehash, it's like, okay. There's, like, this Group over here. Yeah. The the hackathon
track, and it's like, you got twenty four hours. Here's the Amber one hash board. Here's the here's all the repos for Mujina and
The lead engineers are here. And hydropool,
and
and here's, you know, hardware. Here's, like, boxes of, amber ones and control and Libra boards.
Like, see what you guys can do. And then, I mean, you got some parameters like
I like this idea. I like this idea too.
Yeah. Like, we'll we'll do, like,
like, bounties for, like, who can get the most hash rate or, like,
you know, other, like, like, initiatives like that. Holy shit. Yeah. That's actually
Instead of a dance marathon, colleges will do hash marathons.
A dance marathon?
You ever did that in school?
No. I I was just in the library mostly, so I missed the dance marathon.
Rod. We're the nerd we're the nerds, Rod. We're not the only one who oh, boy. I'm not explaining this. That's that's for another episode.
Tune in next time. Rod explains exactly what a dance marathon is. Oh, yeah. Rod,
the author of the Bitcoin miners autumn almanac and also the person that brought you meat spin and cuddle puddle. He's bringing next week the dance marathon.
Gotta get you on those deep memes.
Most recent one is, do you remember the Leroy Jenkins video?
Yeah.
Thumbs up. Let's do this.
No. Scott doesn't know. Ryan doesn't know. What? I do not know. Seriously? You're just next level.
So It's it's a yeah. Tell take us through what the Leroy Jenkins video is, Ico. Alright. I forget, like, what the game is, but it's like a Warcraft.
Oh, a Warcraft game. So it's like a first person shooter game. It's like Doom.
Sure. Yeah. And there's, like, there's, like, a team of players who are all, like, connected remotely playing in the same game, and they're, like, strategizing how they're gonna attack the other team. And so, like, they're all standing in a group, and they're, like, alright. Like, we've got our bravo company set up. We've got our reinforcements coming in from the South. We're gonna head over here. And then all of a sudden, one of the players goes,
Leroy
Jenkins.
And he just, like, leaves the group and starts blasting.
And we're like, wait. Did he just what is he doing? Oh my god. No. Shouldn't oh, and then, like, everybody, like, scrambles, and that's just complete chaos. And then they all get completely annihilated because they blew their elemental size. Yeah. So that's the place. It's like with the headset. Yeah. Yeah.
Ron, that was the video that you saw me watching when you came into the office today, and you were like, do I have to lay this guy off?
Yeah. I come in, and I see him. I'm like, really? That's what we're doing today? And I'm like, it's for a thread. It's for a Twitter thread. He's like, whatever, bro.
Dude, he's doing research.
It's history right now. Anyway, the crux of that is that the Leroy Jenkins video predates the white paper by three years.
Yeah. So if you wanna feel old as heck,
just know that the Leroy Jenkins viral video predates the Bitcoin white paper by three years.
Yeah. I saw one yesterday that said,
in eight months, 2016 will be 10 years old.
Yeah.
Oh.
Wow. Heavy duty.
Oh my gosh. That's
crazy.
Time flies when you're having a good time. Ryan Mhmm. Can't wait to have a great time with you, man. I'm seriously so thankful you're doing this. And,
you know, yes, you're getting compensated for this in,
justifiably,
but there's oh, you have like you, Kopri,
Schnitzel,
Eco, Scott,
maybe not Rob. Like, you guys have a number of amazing opportunities.
Like and to choose this and work on this, it means the world. So thank you so much. Oh, man. Well, I'm so thankful that you guys
spearheaded
this whole thing to make a space
for this stuff to happen. So I'm just
glad to be a part of it. Excited.
Rock and roll, man. You're the man, Ryan.
Let's do it. And, Rob, I love you. You know I do. And I'm so thankful to work with you. All day every day. Every day.
Alright. Thank you, everybody. Alright. Peace out.
It's happening.